const allQuestions = [
  {
    letter: "a",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the only country beside Azerbaijan that starts with an 'A' but doesn't end with an 'A'?",
        answer: "afghanistan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Acetylsalicylic acid is the active ingredient in which incredibly popular and well known drug?",
        answer: "aspirin",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Northern Lights are the Aurora Borealis, what name is given to the Southern Lights?",
        answer: "aurora australis",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "b",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "On which London street is the commemoration statue of fictional character Sherlock Holmes?",
        answer: "baker street",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Belgium, the Netherlands and Luxembourg came together in 1948 to form an economic union, known as what?",
        answer: "benelux",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which spirit is added to sugar and egg yolks to make Advocaat?",
        answer: "brandy",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "c",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points on a curved surface?",
        answer: "caliper",
      },
      {
        question: "In which country was Greenpeace founded in 1971?",
        answer: "canada",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which chemical compound in the body is linked to hardening of the arteries?",
        answer: "cholesterol",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "d",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Best remembered for his fairy tales, what nationality was Hans Christian Andersen?",
        answer: "danish",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What name is given to a doctor who specialises in skin disorders?",
        answer: "dermatologist",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Hills and ridges composed of drifting sand are known as what?",
        answer: "dunes",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "e",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "By what name is the artist Marshall Mathers better known?",
        answer: "eminen",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the early 20th century, rattlesnake venom was used to treat which illness?",
        answer: "epilepsy",
      },
      {
        question: "The study of word origins is called what?",
        answer: "etymology",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "f",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the largest and longest bone in the human body?",
        answer: "femur",
      },
      {
        question: "Which city is the capital of the Italian region of Tuscany?",
        answer: "florence",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the hazelnut liqueur named for the mysterious monk that made it 300 years ago?",
        answer: "frangelico",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "g",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Scientists have been able to segment what into 4 main types: spiral, elliptical, peculiar, and irregular?",
        answer: "galaxies",
      },
      {
        question: "Who directed the 1973 film “American Graffiti”?",
        answer: "george lucas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What name is given to a traditional, flat-bottomed Venetian rowing boat?",
        answer: "gondola",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "h",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "A depilatory is a substance used for removing what?",
        answer: "hair",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The four throwing events at the olympics are shot put, discus, javelin and what?",
        answer: "hammer",
      },
      {
        question: "Which is the most abundant element in the universe?",
        answer: "hydrogen",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "i",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What company was formed by the Swede, Ingvar Kamprad, one of the richest men in the world?",
        answer: "ikea",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the common name for the condition dyspepsia?",
        answer: "indigestion",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosporus Strait?",
        answer: "istanbul",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "j",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "As of 2021, who has received the most Academy Award nominations for any male actor with twelve nominations?",
        answer: "jack nicholson",
      },
      { question: "What is the capital of Indonesia?", answer: "jakarta" },
      {
        question:
          "Actor Jared Leto played the part of which DC Comics character in the 2017 film “Justice League”?",
        answer: "joker",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "k",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Translated as “wooden temples”, what is the name of the capital city of Nepal?",
        answer: "kathmandu",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which food stuff has a name which translates into English as 'On A Skewer'?",
        answer: "kebab",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which fibrous, sulphur-rich protein occurs naturally in hair, horns, hooves and feathers?",
        answer: "keratin",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "l",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Which famous opera house in Milan, Italy, rose to its greatest heights under Toscanini?",
        answer: "la scala",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of acid is produced in the muscles during exercise?",
        answer: "lactic",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the main ingredient of the Indian dish “Dal”?",
        answer: "lentils",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "m",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What Venetian traveller and explorer landed in China and reached Kublai Khan's court in 1275?",
        answer: "marco polo",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In Roman mythology, which God was the father of Romulus and Remus, the founders of Rome?",
        answer: "mars",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest north and is known as 'The Land of 10,000 Lakes'?",
        answer: "minnesota",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "n",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Whose army did Admiral Nelson defeat at the battle of Trafalgar?",
        answer: "napoleon",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was Keanu Reeves' computer world alias in 'The Matrix'?",
        answer: "neo",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the first self-governing country in the world in which all women had the right to vote in parliamentary elections?",
        answer: "new zealand",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "o",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "“Ladies Fingers' ', which can get a bit slimy when the seed pods are cooked, are better known as what?",
        answer: "okra",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Ballad Of Reading Gaol & De Profundis, were written from the experiences of who, while in gaol?",
        answer: "oscar wilde",
      },
      {
        question:
          "As well as being a unit of measurement, what other name is used for the snow leopard?",
        answer: "ounce",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "p",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What now famous painter was once so impoverished that he kept warm by burning his own paintings?",
        answer: "pablo picasso",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which cult 1994 film are all of the clocks stuck on 4:20?",
        answer: "pulp fiction",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the mountain chain separating most of Spain from France?",
        answer: "pyrenees",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "q",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Widely regarded as one of the greatest players to ever play, American football star Tom Brady would be found in what position?",
        answer: "quarterback",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which English cartoonist, caricaturist, illustrator and children's writer has illustrated 18 books written by Roald Dahl?",
        answer: "quentin blake",
      },
      {
        question: "What is another word for “A witty remark”?",
        answer: "quip",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "r",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Which group, from Oxford, England, released the album “O.K. Computer” in 1997?",
        answer: "radiohead",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which modern day country would you find the region known as Transylvania?",
        answer: "romania",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What unit of currency is shared by Sri Lanka, Nepal, and India?",
        answer: "rupee",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "s",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is a box-like funeral receptacle for a corpse, most commonly carved in stone, and usually displayed above ground?",
        answer: "sarcophagus",
      },
      {
        question:
          "When used to describe a camera, what does 'S' in SLR stand for?",
        answer: "single (lens reflex)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Four thirds multiplied by pi multiplied by the radius cubed, gives you the volume of what geometric objects?",
        answer: "spheres",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "t",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What term is used for the speed at which a piece of music is played?",
        answer: "tempo",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What name is given to a great wave resulting from an earthquake?",
        answer: "tsunami",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region in central Italy is regarded as the birthplace of the Italian Renaissance?",
        answer: "tuscany",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "u",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "On TV, who struggles in the publishing business and is rebuked because she doesn't meet the traditional standards of beauty?",
        answer: "ugly betty",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which modernist novel by Irish writer James Joyce was first serialised in parts in the American journal The Little Review?",
        answer: "ulysses",
      },
      {
        question:
          "As of 2021, who is the world record holder in the 100 metres, 200 metres, and 4 X 100 metres relay?",
        answer: "usain bolt",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "v",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is administered to help the immune system develop protection from a disease?",
        answer: "vaccines",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which instrument do you associate with Stradivarius and also the Amati family?",
        answer: "violin",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Translating to 'Ruler of the East', which city lies at the eastern terminus of the Trans-Siberian railway?",
        answer: "vladivostok",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "w",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Released in November 1996, what was the debut single by English girl group the Spice Girls?",
        answer: "wannabe",
      },
      {
        question:
          "James Howlett, also known as Logan is a fictional character from the X-Men, what is his codename?",
        answer: "wolverine",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which song by Miley Cyrus, recorded for her fourth studio album, Bangerz (2013), won the award for World's Best Video at the 2014 World Music Awards?",
        answer: "wrecking ball",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "x",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Also a huge TV franchise, what describes a noteworthy special talent or quality?",
        answer: "x-factor",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Alprazolam is a fast-acting tranquilliser of medium duration in the triazolobenzodiazepine class, sold under what brand name?",
        answer: "xanax",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ethernet was a registered trademark of what company, better known for photocopiers?",
        answer: "xerox",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "y",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What name is given to a length of interlocked fibres, suitable for use in the production of textiles, sewing, knitting, etc?",
        answer: "yarn",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What name is given to a group of physical, mental, and spiritual practices or disciplines which originated in ancient India?",
        answer: "yoga",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which former country existed in Southeast Europe and Central Europe for most of the 20th century and came into existence after World War I in 1918?",
        answer: "yugoslavia",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    letter: "z",
    status: null,
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the capital and largest city of the country Croatia?",
        answer: "zagreb",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Introduced in 1986, which princess is the titular character in a Nintendo video game series?",
        answer: "zelda",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was David Bowie's titular alter ego, a fictional androgynous and bisexual rock star who is sent to Earth as a saviour?",
        answer: "ziggy stardust",
      },
    ],
  },
];

const getGameQuestions = (data) => {
  const getRandomIndex = () => {
    return Math.floor(Math.random() * 3);
  };

  let gameQuestions = data.map((item) => {
    const randomIndex = getRandomIndex();
    return {
      letter: item.letter,
      status: null,
      question: item.questions[randomIndex].question,
      answer: item.questions[randomIndex].answer,
    };
  });
  return gameQuestions;
};

export { allQuestions, getGameQuestions };
